Ives and Pierce Records
© 2010 University of Connecticut
Ives and Pierce Records.
1895-1929.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Ives and Pierce
34 linear feet.
Ives and Pierce, a rural business in Canaan, Connecticut, was owned by Henry B. Ives and Robert D. Pierce, and sold grain, chicken feed, poultry, and agricultural supplies to local farmers. The business also sold coal to local residents. The records consist of 36 volumes of financial journals, daybooks, and coal and account books.
MSS19790008
History
Ives and Pierce, a rural business in Canaan, Connecticut, was owned by Henry B. Ives and Robert D. Pierce, and sold grain, chicken feed, poultry, and agricultural supplies to local farmers. The business also sold coal to local residents.
Scope and Content
The collection contains the financial and business records of Ives and Pierce.
Arrangement
Series I: Journals and Daybooks ( 1895-1929 ) consists of thirty journals and four daybooks which list daily sales made at the store. The entries include the transaction date, the customer's name, a description of the item sold, and the purchase price.
Series II: Coal and Account Books ( 1900-1928 ) consists of two volumes. The first volume lists sales of coal for 1922 to 1928. The second volume is an account book, 1900-1925, which records coal and grain purchased.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of Connecticut business records. For detailed information about this collection please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Ives, Henry B.; Pierce, Robert D.
Places:
Canaan, Conn.
Subjects:
Merchants -- Connecticut.
Document Types:
Administrative Records.; Financial Records.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The Ives and Pierce Records were obtained by the University of Connecticut in the 1950s.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Journals and Daybooks, 1895-1929
  - Journals
    - 1895 August - 1896 December 31 (Box 1)
    - 1898 August 1 - 1899 October 31 (Box 2)
    - 1899 November 1 - 1900 December 22 (Box 3)
    - 1900 December 24 - 1901 December 15 (Box 4)
    - 1902 October 15 - 1903 July 15 (Box 5)
    - 1903 July 25 - 1904 May 15 (Box 6)
    - 1904 May 16 - 1905 April 1 (Box 7)
    - 1905 April 1 - 1906 February 3 (Box 8)
    - 1906 February 4 - 1906 November 30 (Box 9)
    - 1906 December 1 - 1907 September 23 (Box 10)
    - 1907 September 24 - 1908 July 17 (Box 11)
    - 1908 July 17 - 1909 June 1 (Box 12)
    - 1909 June 1 - 1910 March 1 (Box 13)
    - 1910 March 1 - 1910 November 1 (Box 14)
    - 1910 November 1 - 1911 June 19 (Box 15)
    - 1911 June 20 - 1912 February 5 (Box 16)
    - 1912 February 6 - September 20 (Box 17)
    - 1912 September 21 - 1913 August 28 (Box 18)
    - 1913 August 29 - 1914 April 30 (Box 19)
    - 1914 May 1 - November 30 (Box 20)
    - 1914 December 1 - 1915 July 28 (Box 21)
    - 1915 July 29 - 1916 February 29 (Box 22)
    - 1916 March 1 - 1917 May 6 (Box 23)
    - 1917 May 7 - November 16 (Box 24)
    - 1917 November 16 - 1919 March 13 (Box 25)
    - 1919 March 13 - 1920 June 30 (Box 26)
    - 1920 July 1 - 1922 January 28 (Box 27)
    - 1922 January 30 - 1923 October 25 (Box 28)
    - 1923 October 25 -1925 May 14 (Box 29)
    - 1925 May 14 - 1927 October 1 (Box 30)
  - Daybooks
    - 1926 August 13 - 1927 April 28 (Box 31)
    - 1927 April 28 - 1928 January 18 (Box 32)
    - 1928 January 18 - October 18 (Box 33)
    - 1928 October 18 - 1929 July 16 (Box 34)
- Series II: Coal and Account Books, 1900-1928
  - Coal book, 1922 September - 1928 (Box 35)
  - Account book, 1900-1925 (Box 36)